Welcome to Essential Hayek
欢迎来到哈耶克简要
I'm Don Boudreaux
我是Don Boudreaux
professor of economics at George Mason University
乔治梅森大学经济学教授
senior fellow with the Fraser Institute
弗雷泽研究所高级研究员
and blogger at Café Hayek
博客Café Hayek的博主之一
This video was part of the Fraser Institute initiative
本视频是由弗雷泽研究所制作的
to present the key ideas of F.A. Hayek in an easily accessible format
对哈耶克关键思想的通俗介绍
In this video, we explore one of Hayek's best know ideas
本视频将介绍哈耶克最著名的一个思想
and perhaps his most profound insight
可能也是他最重要的洞见
the role of prices in conveying information
价格在传递信息中的作用
All economists understand that people make decision based on the cost they face
经济学家都明白人们基于面临的成本
and the benefits they expect to receive
和预期收益做出决策
In most cases
多数情况下
the key cost of the decision is the price the person faces to purchase a good or service
决策的主要成本是个体为商品或服务所支付的价格
This idea is complex, so let's simplify it with an example
这个观点有点复杂，所以让我们举个栗子
This is Sara
这是Sara
Sara loves coffee
她爱喝咖啡
and prefers Columbian coffee
尤其喜欢哥伦比亚咖啡
which she buys from her local grocery store
她在本地的杂货店购买咖啡
The local store usually sells her favorite coffee to her for 10 dollars
她最爱的咖啡一般卖10美金
Sara doesn't know any of the details or cost
Sara并不了解关于咖啡生产的成本和细节
of how the coffee beans are grown
例如咖啡豆是怎么种植的
the irrigation of the coffee farm
咖啡田的灌溉方法
how the beans are roasted
如何烘焙咖啡豆
or how the coffee is transported to her store
咖啡是怎么运到杂货店的等等
all she knows is her favorite Columbian coffee costs 10 dollars
她只知道她最爱喝的哥伦比亚咖啡卖10美金
and that it's worth to her given the enjoyment she gets from drinking Columbian coffee
并且与她喝咖啡所获得的愉悦相比，这10美金花的值得
but what happens if bad weather in Columbia severely damages the coffee farm field
不过如果哥伦比亚天气变差，咖啡种植地被毁，将会如何？
bad weather and crop damage been fewer coffee beans from Columbian
变差的天气和损毁的咖啡植株意外着更少的哥伦比亚咖啡豆
and that results in the price of Columbia coffee going up
这将导致哥伦比亚咖啡的价格上涨
so when Sara next goes to her local grocery store
所以当Sara下次去杂货店时
she finds the price of her favorite Columbian coffee is now 20 dollars
她发现她最爱的哥伦比亚咖啡现在要卖20美金了
Sara doesn't know why the price went up, nor did she need to know why
Sara既不知道、也不需要知道为什么咖啡涨价了
The increased price sends her a signal that prompts her to make an informed decision
上升的价格促使Sara基于新价格重新做出决定
She can pay 20 dollars for her favorite Columbian coffee
她可以为最爱的咖啡付20块
but, the higher price of the Columbian coffee
不过，哥伦比亚咖啡的价格越高
means that she will have to give up more something else to buy that coffee
意味着她为了买咖啡将不得不更多地放弃购买其他东西
In fact, Sara is likely voluntarily choose to buy another type of coffee
事实上，Sara很可能会自愿去购买另一种
one perhaps even at a lower price than a normal Columbian coffee
比哥伦比亚咖啡便宜的咖啡
say, Indonesian coffee, which costs 9 dollars
比如只要9美金的印尼咖啡
so even though Sara doesn't have any of the information about why the price of Columbian coffee changed
所以即使Sara完全不知道为什么哥伦比亚咖啡的价格上涨了
she makes the same decision based purely on the change in price she observes in her grocery store
她仅仅依靠店里标价做出的决定
that she would have made had she known that a weather disaster in Columbian destroyed that much of that country's coffee crop
与假如她知道哥伦比亚咖啡减产做出的决定会是一致的
What Hayek explained and clarified is that people make decisions as if
哈耶克阐明的正是人们做出的决策就好像
they have incredible amount of information about why the price of good or service is what it is
他们掌握价格变动背后的大量信息一样
when in fact, they have little or no information about why the price is what it is
但其实他们对价格为何如此一无所知
They simply know what the price is and that is sufficient
仅仅知道价格是多少
to prompt each of us to act as if we know vast quantities of facts
就已经足以使人们像掌握了
about economics reality that we can't possibly really know
其实根本无力掌握的大量经济信息那样作出决策
To learn more and download  for free
想要下载和更多了解《哈耶克简要》
visit www.essentialhayek.org
请访问www.essentialhayek.org
翻译 by tcya